You can't escape yourself.
Enemy is a thriller, mystery film directed by Denis Villeneuve.
A mild-mannered college professor discovers a look-alike actor
and delves into the other man's private affairs.
Adam / Anthony, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Mary, played by Mélanie Laurent.
Helen, played by Sarah Gadon.
Mother, played by Isabella Rossellini.
Teacher at School, played by Joshua Peace.
Anthony's Concierge, played by Tim Post.
Enemy is a 2013 psychological thriller film directed
by Denis Villeneuve and produced by M.
Faura and Niv Fichman.
Written by Javier Gullón, it was loosely adapted from
José Saramago's 2002 novel The Double.
The film stars Jake Gyllenhaal in a dual role as two men who are
physically identical, but different in personality.
Mélanie Laurent, Sarah Gadon, and Isabella Rossellini co-star.
It is an international co-production of companies from Spain, France and Canada.
Enemy premiered in the Special Presentation section at the 2013
Toronto International Film Festival on 8 September.
Upon its wide release by A24 on 14 March 2014, the film earned $3.4
million at the box office and received positive reviews.
Enemy earned ten nominations at the 2nd Canadian Screen Awards, winning five, including Best
Director for Villeneuve, and Canadian Screen Award for Best Supporting Actress for Gadon.
It was named Best Canadian Film of the Year at the
Toronto Film Critics Association Awards 2014.
The film explores themes of infidelity, based on novel or
book, nightmare, professor, pregnancy.
The tone is intense and mind_bending.